{
    "id": "14_Health_214",
    "claim": "Lucas Patrick Machado, from  years old, met Celso* on a social network, in July of . Both lived in the city of Cáceres, state of Mato Grosso, and exchanged messages for a couple of weeks. At the end of the month they decided to have dinner together.'I always said that I was nice and cool, that I wanted to meet and that we could be together. That's why we decided to go out ', recalls Machado. The meeting ended in a motel, where they had sex with condoms. 'I had told him that I had no condoms and asked him to take, because he was without money ', says Luke. After the first relationship, Machado was surprised by Celso's attitude, who showed no interest in maintaining contact.'We left and he left me at home. We haven't talked to each other in the next few weeks. I felt used because I thought I might have something serious ', says the young man. Three months later, a phone call shook Machado. 'He (Celso) called me and suggested that I take an HIV test because he had 'leaved me a gift' on the night we shared ', Machado relates. Hours later, Machado received the test results.'The doctor confirmed that I was HIV-positive. I stood still. For me life was over.\". Despite believing he was the victim of intentional transmission of HIV, Lucas Machado chose not to report Celso.'I was #NUMBER* years old and I wasn't mature enough to think of a complaint. If it did happen today, perhaps I would, but I find it very difficult to handle cases like this, because it is very difficult to prove it ', he explains. Although these cases can be considered as isolated events within a population of  people living with HIV in Brazil, situations such as Lucas's expose the HIV-positive dilemma in the face of research difficulties and prejudice in these cases. Sanctions under debateThe transmission of venereal or serious diseases is a crime in Brazil. The Penal Code provides for a penalty of up to one year's imprisonment for those who expose the couple to venereal disease knowing that they are infected. If the transmission is intentional, the penalty goes up to four years in prison. In the case of HIV, a decision of  of the Supreme Court of Justice defines intentional transmission as a very serious bodily injury, a crime that may result in up to eight years of imprisonment. However, entities that support people with HIV and public policy observatories for the disease criticize legislative initiatives that criminalize people with HIV. The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS), for example, calls punitive measures 'unnecessary 'and a 'setback'. UNAIDS notes that there is no evidence that the criminalization of the practice brings benefits to public health. According to the entity, there is a risk of inducing serious errors in the judiciary and deliberate criminalization of people living with the virus. 'Once under threat of being considered a criminal, the person tends to flee health services, avoiding HIV testing, becoming potentially more likely to transmit the virus unintentionally ', states the programme. In fact, for UNAIDS, cases of deliberate spread are isolated due to antiretroviral treatments that reduce the potential for HIV-positive transmission by %. Preconception and uncertaintiesVictims of probable intentional transmissions report that there is prejudice at the time of the complaints.'I filed a complaint in a police station against a man who had relations with me against my will. They started investigating, but in the end they said there was no sexual violence against the man and there was no way to prove that I was intentionally infected. That's one of the things that hurt me the most, because the police didn't even want to help me ', says Luiz, a university student from  years of Rio de Janeiro. The young man relates that he met a man from  years old, who claimed to be a school principal, through an application of relationships in February this year. They talked for two days and marked a meeting at a motel.'He asked to have sex without a condom and told me he didn't have any illness, but I didn't want. Then he used force against me, to prevent me from escaping, and he had intercourse with me without a condom ', he said. The universityman points out that he blocked the aggressor on all his social networks after the sexual act.'I didn't know what to do, because I wasn't going to look for my family or anyone. I preferred to keep what happened to me and hope I didn't get the virus.\". Luiz points out that this was his first condom-free relationship. A month after that unfortunate encounter, she began to get sick frequently.'I had enough fever, took remedies and didn't get better. I recovered a little, but I felt a lot of headache. In March, stains began to appear on my body and I went to do a blood test ', he says. Two days later, he got the result and found out it was HIV positive.'My mother was the first to know and told me. It was horrible, for me the world was over, I didn't know what to do.\". The next day, the university had the first medical consultation and began treatment against the virus. Then he went to a police station to charge his abuser.'I decided to denounce him, but they didn't go deeper into the case. He was wanted by the police and said he didn't know he had HIV. He had to do the test and tested positive ', recalls Luiz. Finally the young man was left with the uncertainty about the intentionality in the transmission.'It's hard to figure out if it was intentional or not, I can't claim he knew, but I think so. Regardless, what he did was wrong, because he had sex with me without a condom, even without my consent ', he concludes. The Civil Police of Rio de Janeiro did not respond to BBC consultations on this report. For its part, the Ministry of Public Security of São Paulo, in a note, denied that there was police negligence in such situations. He stated that victims of possible intentional transmissions are targeted to record cases, and that there is individualized analysis of each fact for the 'criminalization of which crime the act is framed '. IroniesPublicist Lucas Raniel, from  years old, living in Ribeirão Preto, state of Sao Paulo, experienced what are the consequences of accusations about intentional transmission of HIV. He has lived with the virus for three years and became accused of deliberately spreading it.'Last year they created a WhatsApp group with a photo of me and they talked about AIDS going on. That rumor spread and when I discovered it I was shocked ', he relates. At that time, Raniel was in treatment against the virus and had undetectable viral load.'I went to the bars and felt like they were looking at me, a lot of people walked away and I isolated myself. He lived going from faculty to work and from work to home ', says Raniel. The publicist reveals that he reached the end of hanging himself in the window of his room for a whole night.'I was thinking of dying. It's sad to talk about it, but I don't think it's right to stop mentioning it because people think about it and it can't be that way. You can't kill yourself because of a disease, you have to beat it and you don't give yourself up. But evil and prejudice make you close down and give in to a depression you don't even realize 'explains Luke. Raniel discovered HIV positive in December of . He says he thinks he was infected three months earlier, after meeting with a guy he'd met through a mobile app.'I had come home drunk, after a party, and I met the boy. We had a little chat and we met that very night. I went to his house, we kept drinking and I ended up losing my senses. In the middle of the morning he took me to the room, but I have a very vague memory ', he relates. Raniel points out that the next day he remembered that he had a sexual relationship.'I remember little of that night, but I knew he had done it without a condom. I asked him right away and he said he could be calm, because he had nothing.\". Before discovering the virus, Lucas points out that he came looking for the man again.'I started to get sick and I got to look for it on WhatsApp. I told him about what was going on and I told him I hadn't had condom-free sex with anyone else. He became very nervous and blocked me from everything ', he said. Raniel is another young man who believes he has been the victim of intentional transmission of HIV, but chose not to report the case.'There's no way to prove it was intentional, plus, I think a mistake of mine caused it because I was drinking a lot. That's why I didn't report it. I don't have pain, I hope it's okay and don't do it again.\". TrendsThe three young people mentioned in this report comprise a range of population that has shown an increase in infection rates. Ministry of Health data show that the rate of men from  to  years with AIDS almost tripled from  to  (from  cases per  thousand inhabitants to ). There was also a large increase in the range from  to  years (from  cases to  thousand inhabitants to ). Experts suggest that reasons are linked to factors such as the emergence of applications that facilitate casual sexual encounters and the decline of sex education programs in schools. The orientation of the Ministry of Health is to use condoms in sexual relations always. In case of suspected exposure to HIV, the Single Health System offers Post-Exhibition Prophylaxis (PEP), which is an antiretroviral treatment for  days, aimed at preventing infection of the virus. The procedure should be started within a maximum of  hours after contact with HIV. It is estimated that in Brazil there are  a thousand people living with the virus and that they do not yet know it. Other  would already be aware, but do not use medicines. Of the  people living with HIV in Brazil, around  were already diagnosed and  started treatment. I'm sorry.",
    "source": "www.bbc.com",
    "date": "08/07/2017",
    "veracity": 1,
    "claims": [
        {
            "claim": "I he they The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS) his abuser The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS) social network, in July intentional transmission of HIV .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What does UNAIDS stand for?",
                    "answer": "The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS"
                },
                {
                    "question": "In what month and year was HIV transmitted?",
                    "answer": "July"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When did the Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS) start?",
                    "score": 0.8517,
                    "answers": "in July|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does UNAIDS stand for?",
                    "score": 0.7541,
                    "answers": "United Nations|compound\tHIV|pobj\this abuser The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS ) social network ,|appos\tUnited Nations|nmod\tThe Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS )|nmod\tHIV|pobj\tsocial|amod\tThe Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS ) social network ,|appos\tHIV|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is UNAIDS' relationship with HIV/AIDS?",
                    "score": 0.7439,
                    "answers": "that I he they The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS ) his abuser The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS ) social network , in July intentional transmission of HIV|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between HIV/AIDS and UNAIDS?",
                    "score": 0.708,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tI|nmod\the|det\tthey|nmod\tThe|det\tUnited|compound\ton HIV|prep\t/|punct\tAIDS|appos\t(|punct\t)|punct\this|poss\tThe|det\tUnited|nmod\t/|pobj\tAIDS|pobj\t(|punct\t)|punct\t,|punct\tintentional|amod\tin July intentional transmission of HIV|appos\tof HIV|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "AIDS intentional transmission of HIV That rumor I I The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS) Grossome and exchanged messages for a I of I .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What rumor did bbc report on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "AIDS intentional transmission of HIV"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is responsible for the rumor of AIDS intentional transmission of HIV?",
                    "answer": "The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS)"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does UNAIDS stand for?",
                    "score": 0.677,
                    "answers": "The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS )|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between HIV/AIDS and UNAIDS?",
                    "score": 0.6759,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep\tthat AIDS intentional transmission of HIV|dobj\tI I The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS )|appos\texchanged messages for a I of I|conj\tmessages for a I of I|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "me the end of the I Both AIDS to have intentional transmission of HIV he .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did bbc.com report on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "I Both AIDS"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did www.bbc.com report on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "end of the I Both AIDS to have intentional transmission of HIV"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between HIV and HIV?",
                    "score": 0.7902,
                    "answers": "intentional transmission of HIV|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the end of the I Both AIDS?",
                    "score": 0.7724,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that me the end of the I Both AIDS to have intentional transmission of HIV he|ROOT\tthat me the end of the I Both AIDS to have intentional transmission of HIV|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "me 's why Both decided to his the transmission had Lucas Patrick Machado, from  years old .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who was the source of the decision to use Lucas Patrick Machado?",
                    "answer": "me"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How old was Patrick Machado when he was born?",
                    "score": 0.8122,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that me 's why Both decided to his the transmission had Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where was Patrick Machado from?",
                    "score": 0.7989,
                    "answers": "Lucas Patrick Machado , from|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where did Machado get his inspiration for his transmission?",
                    "score": 0.795,
                    "answers": "why Both decided to his the transmission had Lucas Patrick Machado , from|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old is Patrick Machado?",
                    "score": 0.7878,
                    "answers": "Patrick|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the date of Patrick Machado's transmission?",
                    "score": 0.73,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "these cases ended his abuser a motel, he the virus sex I me .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on 08/07/2017 that these cases ended his abuser a motel?",
                    "answer": "www.bbc.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the virus sex I me?",
                    "score": 0.5548,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ta|det\the|dep\tthe|det\tthe virus|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between a virus sex I me and a motel?",
                    "score": 0.5421,
                    "answers": "his abuser a motel , he the virus sex I me|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'Lucas Patrick Machado, from  years old had me Celso* that Lucas Patrick Machado, from  years old his abuser his he me Celso* to take, I the virus he the virus the virus the virus .",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How old was Patrick Machado when he took the virus from his abusers?",
                    "score": 0.7661,
                    "answers": "years old his abuser|dobj\tyears old his abuser his he me Celso|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Patrick Machado take from his abusers?",
                    "score": 0.7548,
                    "answers": "Celso|dobj\this abuser|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Machado do with the virus?",
                    "score": 0.7333,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that ' Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old had me Celso * that Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old his abuser his he me Celso * to take , I the virus he the virus the virus the virus|ROOT\tLucas Patrick Machado , from|nsubj\tthat ' Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old had me Celso * that Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old his abuser his he me Celso * to take , I the virus he the virus the virus the virus|ccomp\the|dep\tthat Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old his abuser his he me Celso * to take , I the virus|dep\tI the virus|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who did Machado take the virus from?",
                    "score": 0.7294,
                    "answers": "his he me|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who did Machado steal the virus from?",
                    "score": 0.7222,
                    "answers": "Lucas Patrick Machado , from  |dep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "After the me relationshipThe Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS) it his The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS) had no interest in its .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who did bbc.com report had no interest in?",
                    "answer": "The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS)"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did UNAIDS say about the Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS?",
                    "score": 0.8688,
                    "answers": "no interest in its|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does UNAIDS stand for?",
                    "score": 0.7952,
                    "answers": "on HIV / AIDS|prep\tit his The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS )|appos\ton HIV / AIDS|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between UNAIDS and HIV/AIDS?",
                    "score": 0.7841,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tAfter the me relationshipThe Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS ) it his The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS )|prep\tthe|det\tUnited|compound\tUnited Nations|compound\tthe me relationshipThe Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS ) it his The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS )|pobj\tHIV|compound\t/|punct\tHIV / AIDS|pobj\t(|punct\t)|punct\tit|dep\tThe|det\tUnited|compound\tUnited Nations|compound\tHIV|compound\t/|punct\tHIV / AIDS|pobj\t(|punct\t)|punct\tthat After the me relationshipThe Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS ) it his The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS ) had no interest in its|ccomp\tno|det\tin its|prep\tits|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is UNAIDS?",
                    "score": 0.7205,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that After the me relationshipThe Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS ) it his The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS ) had no interest in its|ROOT\ton 08/07/2017|prep\this|poss"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "it its I its at home.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 08/07/2017 that it's I its at home?",
                    "answer": "www.bbc.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does thebbc.com website say about it's I its at home?",
                    "score": 0.8434,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people live in the United States?",
                    "score": 0.8091,
                    "answers": "at home|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the name of the home that it is in?",
                    "score": 0.7464,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tit|dep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Brazil haveI to each other a disease few I .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did bbc report on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "haveI to each other a disease few"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did www.bbc.com report that Brazil have to each other?",
                    "answer": "a disease few I"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What disease does Brazil have?",
                    "score": 0.8866,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 08/07/2017|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many diseases does Brazil have?",
                    "score": 0.8781,
                    "answers": "each|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many diseases have been contracted in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.8768,
                    "answers": "to each other|prep\teach other|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many diseases are there in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.8722,
                    "answers": "that Brazil haveI to each other a disease few I|ccomp\ta|det\ta disease few I|dobj\tfew|amod\tfew I|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the disease in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.8044,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that Brazil haveI to each other a disease few I|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Lucas Patrick Machado, from  years old felt used because Lucas Patrick Machado, from  years old thought Lucas Patrick Machado, from  years old might have the couple serious ', says Lucas Patrick Machado, from  years old the case .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What kind of couple did Lucas Patrick Machado think he might have?",
                    "answer": "serious"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Machado think about Machado and Machado?",
                    "score": 0.8142,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old felt used|ccomp\tLucas Patrick Machado , from|nsubj\tthat Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old felt used|dep\tLucas Patrick Machado , from|nsubj\tLucas Patrick Machado , from|ccomp\tLucas Patrick Machado , from|nsubj\t  years old the case|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old is Patrick Machado?",
                    "score": 0.7898,
                    "answers": "because Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old is Machado?",
                    "score": 0.7815,
                    "answers": "old|amod\told|amod\told|amod\told|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the age of Machado and Machado?",
                    "score": 0.7341,
                    "answers": "years old|npadvmod\tyears old|npadvmod\tyears old|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Machado and Machado?",
                    "score": 0.7237,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tLucas|compound\tPatrick|compound\t,|punct\tfrom|prep\tfelt used|advcl\tused|xcomp\tbecause|mark\tLucas|compound\tPatrick|compound\t,|punct\tfrom|prep\tthought Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old might have the couple serious|ccomp\tLucas|compound\tPatrick|compound\tLucas Patrick Machado ,|nsubj\t,|punct\t |dep\tmight|aux\t  years old might have the couple serious|ccomp\tthe|det\tthe couple|nsubj\tthe couple serious|ccomp\t'|punct\t,|punct\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old felt used because Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old thought Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old might have the couple serious ' , says Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old the case|ROOT\tLucas|compound\tPatrick|compound\t,|punct\tfrom|prep\t |dep\tyears|nmod\tthe|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Three months later, a phone call shook Lucas Patrick Machado, from  years old .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What shook Lucas Patrick Machado?",
                    "answer": "a phone call"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How old was Patrick Machado?",
                    "score": 0.8718,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that Three months later , a phone call shook Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old|ROOT\tLucas|compound\tPatrick|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old is Patrick Machado?",
                    "score": 0.855,
                    "answers": "  years old|dep\tyears old|npadvmod\told|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the date of the phone call from Patrick Machado?",
                    "score": 0.7523,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep\tThree months|npadvmod\tLucas Patrick Machado , from|dobj\tfrom|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'Celso* I Celso* me I that a man who had relations with me against my will I a man who had relations with me against my will me IroniesPublicist Lucas Raniel, from  years old, living in Ribeirão Preto, state of Sao Paulo the case I IroniesPublicist Lucas Raniel, from  years old, living in Ribeirão Preto, state of Sao Paulo I IroniesPublicist Lucas Raniel, from  years old, living in Ribeirão Preto, state of Sao Paulo .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.bbc.com report on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "'Celso* I Celso* me I that a man who had relations with me against my will"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where was Lucas Raniel living in Ribeirão Preto?",
                    "score": 0.8209,
                    "answers": "me IroniesPublicist Lucas Raniel , from|appos\tI IroniesPublicist Lucas Raniel , from|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old was Lucas Raniel when he lived in Ribeirão Preto?",
                    "score": 0.7919,
                    "answers": "  years old , living in Ribeirão Preto , state of Sao Paulo|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old was the man who had relations with me against my will?",
                    "score": 0.748,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that ' Celso * I Celso * me I that a man who had relations with me me IroniesPublicist Lucas Raniel , from against my will I a man who had relations with me against my will   years old , living in Ribeirão Preto , state of Sao Paulo the case I IroniesPublicist Lucas Raniel , from   years old , living in Ribeirão Preto , state of Sao Paulo|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where did Lucas Raniel live?",
                    "score": 0.7426,
                    "answers": "state of Sao Paulo|appos\tstate of Sao Paulo|appos\tstate of Sao Paulo|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "IroniesPublicist Lucas Raniel, from  years old, living in Ribeirão Preto, state of Sao Paulo a guy he'd met through a mobile app results.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Where was Lucas Raniel from?",
                    "answer": "Sao Paulo"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where did Lucas Raniel live in Ribeirão Preto?",
                    "score": 0.8317,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\tfrom|prep\t |dep\tstate of Sao Paulo|appos\tof Sao Paulo|prep\tSao|compound\t'd|aux\tthrough a mobile app results|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old was Lucas Raniel in Ribeirão Preto?",
                    "score": 0.8196,
                    "answers": "old|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Raniel meet through a mobile app?",
                    "score": 0.8116,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that IroniesPublicist Lucas Raniel , from   years old , living in Ribeirão Preto , state of Sao Paulo a guy he 'd met through a mobile app results|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who did Raniel meet in Ribeirão Preto?",
                    "score": 0.8104,
                    "answers": "that IroniesPublicist Lucas Raniel , from   years old , living in Ribeirão Preto , state of Sao Paulo a guy he 'd met through a mobile app results|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where was Lucas Raniel living in Ribeirão Preto?",
                    "score": 0.8101,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "a man who had relations with me against my will doctor confirmed that Lucas Patrick Machado, from  years old was HIV-positive.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of HIV was Lucas Patrick Machado?",
                    "answer": "HIV-positive"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How old was Patrick Machado when he became HIV-positive?",
                    "score": 0.8325,
                    "answers": "that Lucas Patrick Machado , from   years old|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old is Patrick Machado?",
                    "score": 0.7912,
                    "answers": "old|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Patrick Machado's HIV-positive status?",
                    "score": 0.7723,
                    "answers": "Patrick|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was the doctor who confirmed that Patrick Machado was HIV-positive?",
                    "score": 0.7591,
                    "answers": "doctor|pobj\tLucas|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Patrick Machado being HIV-positive?",
                    "score": 0.7513,
                    "answers": "from|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "For me life the virus .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 08/07/2017 that For me life the virus was for me?",
                    "answer": "www.bbc.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the virus?",
                    "score": 0.7376,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that For me life the virus|ROOT\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tFor me|prep\tme|pobj\tthe|det\tthe virus|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the definition of the virus?",
                    "score": 0.6969,
                    "answers": "that For me life the virus|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "IroniesPublicist Lucas Raniel, from  years old, living in Ribeirão Preto, state of Sao Paulo believing HIV victim of They transmission HIV Lucas Machado me .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Lucas Raniel believe he was a victim of?",
                    "answer": "They transmission HIV Lucas Machado"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where did Lucas Raniel live in Ribeirão Preto?",
                    "score": 0.8229,
                    "answers": "Ribeirão|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old is Lucas Raniel?",
                    "score": 0.8053,
                    "answers": "  years old , living in Ribeirão Preto , state of Sao Paulo|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where was Lucas Raniel living in Ribeirão Preto?",
                    "score": 0.7989,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that IroniesPublicist Lucas Raniel , from   years old , living in Ribeirão Preto , state of Sao Paulo believing HIV victim of They transmission HIV Lucas Machado me|ROOT\ton 08/07/2017|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old was Lucas Raniel in Ribeirão Preto?",
                    "score": 0.7989,
                    "answers": "old|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the death of Lucas Raniel?",
                    "score": 0.7334,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tIroniesPublicist|compound\t |dep\tSao|compound\tHIV|compound\tof They transmission HIV|prep\tThey|nmod\tThey transmission HIV|pobj\tHIV|appos\tme|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "me I me enough to think of a complaint.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 08/07/2017 that me Is enough to think of a complaint?",
                    "answer": "www.bbc.com"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How much did www.bbc.com report on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "enough to think of a complaint"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many complaints are there each year?",
                    "score": 0.9118,
                    "answers": "to think of a complaint|xcomp\tof a complaint|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many complaints have been made in the last year?",
                    "score": 0.8875,
                    "answers": "that me I me enough to think of a complaint|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the complaints filed against the government in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.7691,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "If it did happen today, perhaps I would, but I find it very difficult to handle cases like this, because it is very difficult to prove it ', he explains.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is it very difficult to do in a case like this?",
                    "answer": "prove it"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How difficult is it to prove cases like this?",
                    "score": 0.8221,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that If it did happen today , perhaps I would , but I find it very difficult to handle cases like this , because it is very difficult to prove it '|ccomp\tI find it very difficult to handle cases like this , because it is very difficult to prove it|conj\tvery difficult|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does it take to handle cases like this?",
                    "score": 0.7921,
                    "answers": "to handle cases like this|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What would it take to prove a case like this if it happened today?",
                    "score": 0.7341,
                    "answers": "that If it did happen today , perhaps I would , but I find it very difficult to handle cases like this , because it is very difficult to prove it|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the number of cases that were reported in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.6798,
                    "answers": "If it did happen today|advcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Although these cases can be considered as isolated events within a population of  people living with HIV in Brazil, situations such as Lucas's expose the HIV-positive dilemma in the face of research difficulties and prejudice in these cases.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is one of the reasons why Lucas's cases expose the HIV-positive dilemma?",
                    "answer": "research difficulties"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people live with HIV in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.8443,
                    "answers": "can|aux\tAlthough these cases can be considered as isolated events within a population of|advcl\tas isolated events within a population of|prep\tisolated events within a population of|pobj\twithin a population of|prep\tthat Although these cases can be considered as isolated events within a population of   people living with HIV in Brazil|dep\tin the face of research difficulties and prejudice in these cases|prep\tthe face of research difficulties and prejudice in these cases|pobj\tof research difficulties and prejudice in these cases|prep\tresearch|compound\tresearch difficulties and prejudice in these cases|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many HIV-positive people live in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.8084,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep\tisolated|amod\tsituations such as Lucas 's|nsubj\tsuch as Lucas 's|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the HIV-positive dilemma in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.7521,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that Although these cases can be considered as isolated events within a population of   people living with HIV in Brazil , situations such as Lucas 's expose the HIV - positive dilemma in the face of research difficulties and prejudice in these cases|ROOT\tthat|mark\tAlthough|mark\tthese|det\tthese cases|nsubjpass\tbe|auxpass\ta|det\tof|prep\tpeople living with HIV in Brazil|pobj\tliving with HIV in Brazil|acl\twith HIV|prep\tHIV|pobj\tin Brazil|prep\t,|punct\tsuch|amod\tLucas 's|pobj\t's|case\t, situations such as Lucas 's expose the HIV - positive dilemma in the face of research difficulties and prejudice in these cases|ccomp\tthe|det\tHIV|npadvmod\t-|punct\tHIV - positive|amod\tthe HIV - positive dilemma|dobj\tthe|det\tand|cc\tin these cases|prep\tthese|det\tthese cases|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between HIV and prejudice in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.7328,
                    "answers": "prejudice|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Sanctions under debateThe transmission of venereal or serious diseases is a crime in Brazil.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is a crime in Brazil?",
                    "answer": "transmission of venereal or serious diseases"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the crime in Brazil for transmission of venereal or serious diseases?",
                    "score": 0.8039,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tdebateThe transmission of venereal or serious diseases|nsubj\tof venereal or serious diseases|prep\tvenereal or serious diseases|pobj\tthat Sanctions under debateThe transmission of venereal or serious diseases is a crime in Brazil|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is a crime in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.7741,
                    "answers": "a crime|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the definition of illegal activity in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.7445,
                    "answers": "Sanctions under|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The Penal Code provides for a penalty of up to one year's imprisonment for those who expose the couple to venereal disease knowing that they are infected.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the penalty for exposing a couple to venereal disease knowing that they are infected?",
                    "answer": "up to one year's imprisonment"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the punishments for those who expose a couple to venereal disease knowing they are infected?",
                    "score": 0.6974,
                    "answers": "up to one year 's|poss"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "If the transmission is intentional, the penalty goes up to four years in prison.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How long is the penalty for intentional transmission?",
                    "answer": "up to four years"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the penalty if the transmission is intentional?",
                    "score": 0.7309,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that If the transmission is intentional , the penalty goes up to four years in prison|ROOT\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tIf|mark\tthe|det\tthe transmission|nsubj\tIf the transmission is intentional|advcl\t,|punct\tthe|det\tthe penalty|nsubj\tthat If the transmission is intentional , the penalty goes up to four years in prison|ccomp\tup|quantmod\tto|quantmod\tup to four|nummod\tin prison|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In the case of HIV, a decision of  of the Supreme Court of Justice defines intentional transmission as a very serious bodily injury, a crime that may result in up to eight years of imprisonment.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many years of imprisonment is possible in the case of intentional transmission of HIV?",
                    "answer": "eight years"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does the Supreme Court of justice say about intentional transmission?",
                    "score": 0.8038,
                    "answers": "that may result in up to eight years of imprisonment|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the definition of intentional transmission as a serious bodily injury?",
                    "score": 0.6981,
                    "answers": "that In the case of HIV , a decision of   of the Supreme Court of Justice|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is intentional transmission?",
                    "score": 0.696,
                    "answers": "intentional|amod\tintentional transmission|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the punishment for intentional transmission?",
                    "score": 0.6885,
                    "answers": "of imprisonment|prep\timprisonment|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "However, entities that support people with HIV and public policy observatories for the disease criticize legislative initiatives that criminalize people with HIV.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What do entities that support people with HIV and public policy observatories for the disease criticize?",
                    "answer": "legislative initiatives that criminalize people with HIV"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the laws that criminalize people with HIV and public policy observatories for the disease?",
                    "score": 0.7917,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat criminalize people with HIV|relcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS), for example, calls punitive measures 'unnecessary 'and a 'setback'.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What does UNAIDS call 'unnecessary'?",
                    "answer": "punitive measures"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does UNAIDS say about punitive measures on HIV/AIDS?",
                    "score": 0.9371,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tThe|det\tUnited|compound\t/|punct\t(|punct\t)|punct\t,|punct\t,|punct\t'|punct\t'|punct\tand|cc\ta|det\t'|punct\t'|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What measures does UNAIDS take to combat HIV/AIDS?",
                    "score": 0.9364,
                    "answers": "punitive|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the punitive measures taken by UNAIDS on HIV/AIDS?",
                    "score": 0.8799,
                    "answers": "punitive measures|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does UNAIDS stand for?",
                    "score": 0.8753,
                    "answers": "United Nations|compound\tThe Joint United Nations Programme on HIV / AIDS ( UNAIDS|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS)?",
                    "score": 0.8472,
                    "answers": "Joint|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "UNAIDS notes that there is no evidence that the criminalization of the practice brings benefits to public health.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who noted that there was no evidence that criminalization of HIV brings benefits to public health?",
                    "answer": "UNAIDS"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does criminalization of the practice bring benefits to public health?",
                    "score": 0.7728,
                    "answers": "the criminalization of the practice|nsubj\tbenefits|dobj\tto public health|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does it mean to be criminalized?",
                    "score": 0.7257,
                    "answers": "of the practice|prep\tthe practice|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "According to the entity, there is a risk of inducing serious errors in the judiciary and deliberate criminalization of people living with the virus.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the risk of inducing?",
                    "answer": "serious errors in the judiciary"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people are living with the virus?",
                    "score": 0.6706,
                    "answers": "of people living with the virus|prep\tpeople living with the virus|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'Once under threat of being considered a criminal, the person tends to flee health services, avoiding HIV testing, becoming potentially more likely to transmit the virus unintentionally ', states the programme.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How does a person become more likely to transmit the virus?",
                    "answer": "unintentionally"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people flee health services to avoid HIV testing?",
                    "score": 0.752,
                    "answers": "the programme|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the rate of HIV virus unintentionally?",
                    "score": 0.7058,
                    "answers": "potentially more likely to transmit the virus unintentionally|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of people who flee health services being under threat of being considered criminal?",
                    "score": 0.691,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between fleeing health services and becoming infected with HIV?",
                    "score": 0.6856,
                    "answers": "to flee health services , avoiding HIV testing , becoming potentially more likely to transmit the virus unintentionally|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the HIV testing program?",
                    "score": 0.6197,
                    "answers": "HIV testing|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In fact, for UNAIDS, cases of deliberate spread are isolated due to antiretroviral treatments that reduce the potential for HIV-positive transmission by %.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What reduces the potential for HIV-positive transmission by %?",
                    "answer": "antiretroviral treatments"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many cases of deliberate spread are isolated due to antiretroviral treatments?",
                    "score": 0.8212,
                    "answers": "fact|pobj\t,|punct\t,|punct\tare|auxpass\tto|pcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is antiretroviral treatment for UNAIDS?",
                    "score": 0.8007,
                    "answers": "antiretroviral|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the potential for HIV-positive transmission by %?",
                    "score": 0.7828,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that In fact , for UNAIDS , cases of deliberate spread are isolated due to antiretroviral treatments that reduce the potential for HIV - positive transmission by %|ROOT\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tIn fact|prep\tfor UNAIDS|prep\tof deliberate spread|prep\tdeliberate spread|pobj\tdue to antiretroviral treatments that reduce the potential for HIV - positive transmission by %|prep\tantiretroviral treatments that reduce the potential for HIV - positive transmission by %|pobj\tthat reduce the potential for HIV - positive transmission by %|relcl\tthe potential for HIV - positive transmission|dobj\tfor HIV - positive transmission|prep\tHIV|npadvmod\tHIV - positive|amod\tHIV - positive transmission|pobj\tby %|prep\t%|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between HIV-positive transmission and UNAIDS?",
                    "score": 0.7574,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tthat|nsubj\tthe|det\t-|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Preconception and uncertaintiesVictims of probable intentional transmissions report that there is prejudice at the time of the complaints.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.bbc.com report that there was prejudice at the time of the complaints?",
                    "answer": "Preconception and uncertaintiesVictims of probable intentional transmissions"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many complaints were there at the time of intentional transmissions?",
                    "score": 0.7493,
                    "answers": "that there is prejudice at the time of the complaints|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the evidence of intentional transmissions?",
                    "score": 0.6883,
                    "answers": "of probable intentional transmissions|prep\tprobable intentional transmissions|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the history of intentional transmissions?",
                    "score": 0.6846,
                    "answers": "the complaints|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the time of the complaints?",
                    "score": 0.646,
                    "answers": "at the time of the complaints|prep\tthe time of the complaints|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between conspiracy and intentional transmissions?",
                    "score": 0.616,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 08/07/2017|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'I filed a complaint in a police station against a man who had relations with me against my will.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.bbc.com report on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "'I filed a complaint in a police station against a man who had relations with me against my will"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who filed a complaint against a man who had relations with me against my will?",
                    "score": 0.7752,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\t'|punct\tI|nsubj\ta|det\ta|det\tpolice|compound\ta|det\twho|nsubj\twith me|prep\tme|pobj\tmy|poss"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "They started investigating, but in the end they said there was no sexual violence against the man and there was no way to prove that I was intentionally infected.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the bbc say about the investigation?",
                    "answer": "there was no sexual violence against the man"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the FBI say about the alleged sexual assault?",
                    "score": 0.8254,
                    "answers": "no|det\tno|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the evidence of the infected man being intentionally infected?",
                    "score": 0.7224,
                    "answers": "no way to prove that I was intentionally infected|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the evidence of sexual violence against the man?",
                    "score": 0.7171,
                    "answers": "no sexual violence against the man|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the outcome of the investigation into the man being infected?",
                    "score": 0.6641,
                    "answers": "that They started investigating , but in the end they said there was no sexual violence against the man and there was no way to prove that I was intentionally infected|ccomp\tinvestigating|xcomp\tin the end|prep\tthe end|pobj\tin the end they said there was no sexual violence against the man and there was no way to prove that I was intentionally infected|conj\tthere was no sexual violence against the man and there was no way to prove that I was intentionally infected|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was the man that was infected by the virus?",
                    "score": 0.6476,
                    "answers": "the man|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "That's one of the things that hurt me the most, because the police didn't even want to help me ', says Luiz, a university student from  years of Rio de Janeiro.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was one of the things that hurt Luiz the most?",
                    "answer": "the police didn't even want to help me"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did the police help Luiz?",
                    "score": 0.885,
                    "answers": "to help me|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Why did the police want to help Luiz?",
                    "score": 0.8826,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tthat|nsubj\t'|punct\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that That 's one of the things that hurt me the most , because the police did n't even want to help me ' , says Luiz , a university student from   years of Rio de Janeiro|ROOT\tfrom|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the police do to help Luiz?",
                    "score": 0.7922,
                    "answers": "the things that hurt me the most , because the police did n't even want to help me|pobj\tthat hurt me the most , because the police did n't even want to help me|relcl\tbecause the police did n't even want to help me|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the university where Luis Luiz graduated from?",
                    "score": 0.6552,
                    "answers": "Luiz , a university student from|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Luis Ortiz and the police?",
                    "score": 0.614,
                    "answers": "  years of Rio de Janeiro|dep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The young man relates that he met a man from  years old, who claimed to be a school principal, through an application of relationships in February this year.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How did a young man describe meeting a man who claimed to be a school principal?",
                    "answer": "through an application of relationships"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How old was the man who claimed to be a school principal?",
                    "score": 0.6937,
                    "answers": "old|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who did the man meet in February of 2017?",
                    "score": 0.6597,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that The young man relates that he met a man from   years old , who claimed to be a school principal , through an application of relationships in February this year|ROOT\ton 08/07/2017|prep\t08/07/2017|pobj\tthat|mark\tThe|det\tThe young man|nsubj\tthat The young man relates that he met a man from|ccomp\tthat|mark\the|nsubj\tthat he met a man from|ccomp\ta|det\ta man from|dobj\tfrom|prep\t,|punct\twho|nsubj\twho claimed to be a school principal , through an application of relationships|relcl\tto|aux\ta|det\tschool|compound\t,|punct\tan|det\tin February this year|prep\tthis|det\tthis year|npadvmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between a man and a school principal?",
                    "score": 0.6163,
                    "answers": "to be a school principal|xcomp\ta school principal|attr\tthrough an application of relationships|prep\tan application of relationships|pobj\tof relationships|prep\trelationships|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between the man and the young man?",
                    "score": 0.5759,
                    "answers": "young|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "They talked for two days and marked a meeting at a motel.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How long did the bbc and bbc talk on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "two days"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where did the meeting take place?",
                    "score": 0.7744,
                    "answers": "at a motel|prep\ta motel|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many days was the meeting held at a motel?",
                    "score": 0.7266,
                    "answers": "two|nummod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the meeting?",
                    "score": 0.685,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that They talked for two days and marked a meeting at a motel|ROOT\tthat|mark\tThey|nsubj\tthat They talked for two days and marked a meeting at a motel|ccomp\tfor two days|prep\tand|cc\tmarked a meeting at a motel|conj\ta|det\ta|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the hotel where the meeting took place?",
                    "score": 0.5949,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'He asked to have sex without a condom and told me he didn't have any illness, but I didn't want.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.bbc.com report on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "'He asked to have sex without a condom and told me he didn't have any illness,"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the man who asked to have sex without condoms?",
                    "score": 0.7564,
                    "answers": "without a condom|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between sex without condoms and illness?",
                    "score": 0.732,
                    "answers": "to have sex without a condom|xcomp\tsex|dobj\ta condom|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the relationship between the man and the condom?",
                    "score": 0.6593,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Then he used force against me, to prevent me from escaping, and he had intercourse with me without a condom ', he said.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How did the bbc report that he had intercourse with me?",
                    "answer": "without a condom"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of intercourse with the man without a condom?",
                    "score": 0.7073,
                    "answers": "that Then he used force against me , to prevent me from escaping , and he had intercourse with me without a condom|ccomp\tfrom escaping|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the man who used force against me and the woman who had intercourse without a condom?",
                    "score": 0.6851,
                    "answers": "Then|advmod\the|nsubj\tand|cc\the|nsubj\the|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The universityman points out that he blocked the aggressor on all his social networks after the sexual act.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the universityman do after the sexual act?",
                    "answer": "he blocked the aggressor on all his social networks"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did the aggressor block social networks after the sexual act?",
                    "score": 0.8411,
                    "answers": "after the sexual act|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the universityman who blocked the aggressor?",
                    "score": 0.6168,
                    "answers": "The universityman|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between the professor and the aggressor?",
                    "score": 0.5974,
                    "answers": "social|amod\tsexual|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'I didn't know what to do, because I wasn't going to look for my family or anyone.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the cause of death of Gary Johnson?",
                    "score": 0.7194,
                    "answers": "did|aux"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Scott Walker's family?",
                    "score": 0.6299,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that ' I did n't know what to do , because I was n't going to look for my family or anyone|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the reason for not looking for his family or anyone?",
                    "score": 0.6077,
                    "answers": "that ' I did n't know what to do , because I was n't going to look for my family or anyone|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between looking for your family and looking for someone else?",
                    "score": 0.5771,
                    "answers": "what to do|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the person who did not know what to do with their family?",
                    "score": 0.5306,
                    "answers": "for my family or anyone|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "I preferred to keep what happened to me and hope I didn't get the virus.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did bbc.com report on 08/07/2017",
                    "answer": "I preferred to keep what happened to me and hope I didn't get the virus"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Dr. George Flinn say about the virus?",
                    "score": 0.7991,
                    "answers": "to keep what happened to me and hope I did n't get the virus|xcomp\tdid|aux\tn't|neg"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Dr. George Flinn's virus?",
                    "score": 0.711,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\tthat I preferred to keep what happened to me and hope I did n't get the virus|ccomp\twhat happened to me|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the virus that Dr. George Flinn contracted from?",
                    "score": 0.6641,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Luiz points out that this was his first condom-free relationship.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who said this was his first condom-free relationship?",
                    "answer": "Luiz"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many condom-free relationships has Luis Ortiz had?",
                    "score": 0.9184,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many condoms did Luiz have in his first relationship?",
                    "score": 0.887,
                    "answers": "out|prt\t-|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between a condom and a condom?",
                    "score": 0.7962,
                    "answers": "his first condom - free relationship|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the condom-free relationship?",
                    "score": 0.7709,
                    "answers": "condom|npadvmod\tcondom - free|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "A month after that unfortunate encounter, she began to get sick frequently.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on the incident on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "bbc.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When did she start getting sick?",
                    "score": 0.9147,
                    "answers": "that A month after that unfortunate encounter , she began to get sick frequently|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many days after the incident did she get sick?",
                    "score": 0.8406,
                    "answers": "A month after that unfortunate encounter|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people were sick after the incident?",
                    "score": 0.8029,
                    "answers": "that unfortunate encounter|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between getting sick and getting sick?",
                    "score": 0.7746,
                    "answers": "to get sick frequently|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the number of sick people after the encounter?",
                    "score": 0.6852,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'I had enough fever, took remedies and didn't get better.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Dr. George Flinn say about the flu?",
                    "score": 0.8448,
                    "answers": "that ' I had enough fever , took remedies and did n't get better|ccomp\ttook remedies and did n't get better|conj\tdid|aux\tn't|neg"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the cause of the flu in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.7732,
                    "answers": "did n't get better|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the symptoms of the flu?",
                    "score": 0.7504,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that ' I had enough fever , took remedies and did n't get better|ROOT\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tremedies|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the flu and the flu?",
                    "score": 0.7414,
                    "answers": "better|acomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "I recovered a little, but I felt a lot of headache.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the bbc report that I felt a lot of on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "headache"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many headaches did the doctor feel after he recovered?",
                    "score": 0.9056,
                    "answers": "that I recovered a little , but I felt a lot of headache|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the cause of the headache?",
                    "score": 0.8759,
                    "answers": "but|cc"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the symptoms of headache?",
                    "score": 0.8414,
                    "answers": "I felt a lot of headache|conj\ta lot of headache|dobj\tof headache|prep\theadache|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In March, stains began to appear on my body and I went to do a blood test ', he says.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did he do when stains began to appear on his body?",
                    "answer": "a blood test"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When did stains appear on Scott Walker's body?",
                    "score": 0.8514,
                    "answers": "In March|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "When did stains start showing on a person's body?",
                    "score": 0.8421,
                    "answers": "stains|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many blood tests were performed on Scott Walker in March 2017?",
                    "score": 0.7586,
                    "answers": "to appear on my body|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of stains on Scott Walker's body in March 2017?",
                    "score": 0.694,
                    "answers": "on my body|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the blood test?",
                    "score": 0.6638,
                    "answers": "to do a blood test|advcl\ta blood test|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Two days later, he got the result and found out it was HIV positive.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the result of the test?",
                    "answer": "HIV positive"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the results of the HIV positive test?",
                    "score": 0.8301,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that Two days later , he got the result and found out it was HIV positive|ROOT\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tTwo|nummod\t,|punct\the|nsubj\tthe|det\tthe result|dobj\tand|cc\tfound out it was HIV positive|conj\tout|prt\tit|nsubj\tit was HIV positive|ccomp\tHIV positive|attr\tpositive|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'My mother was the first to know and told me.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.bbc.com report on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "'My mother was the first to know and told me"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who was the first person to know the mother of Barack Obama?",
                    "score": 0.8724,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that ' My mother was the first to know and told me|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "It was horrible, for me the world was over, I didn't know what to do.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did bbc.com report on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "the world was over, I didn't know what to do"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When did the world end?",
                    "score": 0.8641,
                    "answers": "over|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the author of the article say about the world being over?",
                    "score": 0.789,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tIt|nsubj\t,|punct\tme|pobj\tthe|det\t,|punct\tI|nsubj\tdid|aux\tn't|neg\twhat|dobj\tto|aux"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between the FBI and the terrorist attacks?",
                    "score": 0.7276,
                    "answers": "It was horrible|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the world doing when the world was over?",
                    "score": 0.7082,
                    "answers": "horrible|acomp\twhat to do|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of thebbc.com website?",
                    "score": 0.5956,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The next day, the university had the first medical consultation and began treatment against the virus.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did bbc.com report that the university had its first medical consultation?",
                    "answer": "08/07/2017"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the treatment for the virus?",
                    "score": 0.7595,
                    "answers": "treatment against the virus|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the first medical consultation at Washington University?",
                    "score": 0.7544,
                    "answers": "the university|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Then he went to a police station to charge his abuser.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did he do to charge his abuser?",
                    "answer": "he went to a police station"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where did the alleged abuse take place?",
                    "score": 0.8834,
                    "answers": "to a police station|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of charging your abusers?",
                    "score": 0.816,
                    "answers": "to charge his abuser|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the alleged abuse committed at a police station in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.7932,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'I decided to denounce him, but they didn't go deeper into the case.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the FBI do to denounce him?",
                    "score": 0.8731,
                    "answers": "that ' I decided to denounce him , but they did n't go deeper into the case|ccomp\tto denounce him|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Did the FBI go deeper into the case?",
                    "score": 0.862,
                    "answers": "they did n't go deeper into the case|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the outcome of the case against Trump?",
                    "score": 0.7907,
                    "answers": "the case|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the accusation against Trump?",
                    "score": 0.7745,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep\tn't|neg"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the man that was accused of being a terrorist?",
                    "score": 0.6806,
                    "answers": "I|nsubj\thim|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "He was wanted by the police and said he didn't know he had HIV.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did he say about being wanted by the police?",
                    "answer": "he didn't know he had HIV"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did the police know he had HIV?",
                    "score": 0.9092,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that He was wanted by the police and said he did n't know he had HIV|ROOT\tHe|nsubjpass\twas|auxpass\tthe|det\tand|cc\tsaid he did n't know he had HIV|conj\the|nsubj\tdid|aux\tn't|neg\the did n't know he had HIV|ccomp\the|nsubj\the had HIV|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between HIV and HIV?",
                    "score": 0.8012,
                    "answers": "HIV|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the police who wanted him?",
                    "score": 0.7641,
                    "answers": "by the police|agent\tthe police|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "He had to do the test and tested positive ', recalls Luiz.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was Luiz's score when he did the test?",
                    "answer": "positive"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the results of the test?",
                    "score": 0.8383,
                    "answers": "that He had to do the test and tested positive|ccomp\tthe test|dobj\ttested positive|conj\tpositive|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the test?",
                    "score": 0.812,
                    "answers": "to do the test|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the test that he tested on?",
                    "score": 0.8046,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Finally the young man was left with the uncertainty about the intentionality in the transmission.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the young man left with the uncertainty about in the transmission?",
                    "answer": "the intentionality"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Why was the man left with the uncertainty about the intentionality in the transmission?",
                    "score": 0.7937,
                    "answers": "the uncertainty about the intentionality in the transmission|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did the man say about the intentionality of the transmission?",
                    "score": 0.6955,
                    "answers": "that Finally the young man was left with the uncertainty about the intentionality in the transmission|ccomp\tthe transmission|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between intentionality and transmission?",
                    "score": 0.5594,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that Finally the young man was left with the uncertainty about the intentionality in the transmission|ROOT\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tFinally|advmod\tthe|det\twith the uncertainty about the intentionality in the transmission|prep\tthe|det\tthe|det\tin the transmission|prep\tthe|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Regardless, what he did was wrong, because he had sex with me without a condom, even without my consent ', he concludes.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did bbc report was wrong?",
                    "answer": "he had sex with me without a condom, even without my consent"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does thebbc.com website say about a condom?",
                    "score": 0.75,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between a condom and sex?",
                    "score": 0.7132,
                    "answers": "because|mark\tsex|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between the man who had sex with me without a condom?",
                    "score": 0.7123,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that Regardless , what he did was wrong , because he had sex with me without a condom , even without my consent|ccomp\twhat he did|csubj\tthat Regardless , what he did was wrong , because he had sex with me without a condom , even without my consent|ccomp\twrong|acomp\tbecause he had sex with me without a condom , even without my consent|advcl\twith me|prep\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that Regardless , what he did was wrong , because he had sex with me without a condom , even without my consent ' , he concludes|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The Civil Police of Rio de Janeiro did not respond to BBC consultations on this report.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who did not respond to BBC consultations?",
                    "answer": "The Civil Police of Rio de Janeiro"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did the police respond to BBC consultations on the report?",
                    "score": 0.8999,
                    "answers": "Rio de Janeiro|pobj\ton this report|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the response of the Civil Police of Rio de Janeiro to BBC consultations?",
                    "score": 0.8181,
                    "answers": "BBC consultations on this report|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "For its part, the Ministry of Public Security of São Paulo, in a note, denied that there was police negligence in such situations.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 08/07/2017 that the Ministry of Public Security of So Paulo denied that there was police negligence in such situations?",
                    "answer": "www.bbc.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did the Ministry of Public Security of São Paulo deny that there was police negligence in such situations?",
                    "score": 0.8743,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that For its part , the Ministry of Public Security of São Paulo , in a note , denied that there was police negligence in such situations|ROOT\tthat For its part , the Ministry of Public Security of São Paulo , in a note , denied that there was police negligence in such situations|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "He stated that victims of possible intentional transmissions are targeted to record cases, and that there is individualized analysis of each fact for the 'criminalization of which crime the act is framed '.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What does the individualized analysis of each fact allow for thecriminalization of?",
                    "answer": "which crime the act is framed"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the analysis of each fact for the criminalization of which crime the act is framed?",
                    "score": 0.7146,
                    "answers": "individualized|amod\tof each fact|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the definition of intentional transmissions?",
                    "score": 0.6855,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that He stated that victims of possible intentional transmissions are targeted to record cases , and that there is individualized analysis of each fact for the ' criminalization of which crime the act is framed '|ROOT\tthat|mark\tHe|nsubj\tthat|mark\tvictims of possible intentional transmissions|nsubjpass\tof possible intentional transmissions|prep\tpossible|amod\tintentional|amod\tpossible intentional transmissions|pobj\tare|auxpass\tthat victims of possible intentional transmissions are targeted to record cases , and that there is individualized analysis of each fact for the ' criminalization of which crime the act is framed '|advcl\tto record cases|prep\trecord|compound\trecord cases|pobj\t,|punct\tand|cc\tthat|mark\tthere|expl\tthe|det\t'|punct\twhich|det\twhich crime|pcomp\tthe|det\tthe act|nsubjpass\tis|auxpass\t'|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "IroniesPublicist Lucas Raniel, from  years old, living in Ribeirão Preto, state of Sao Paulo, experienced what are the consequences of accusations about intentional transmission of HIV.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who was Lucas Raniel?",
                    "answer": "IroniesPublicist"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where did Lucas Raniel live in Ribeirão Preto?",
                    "score": 0.8599,
                    "answers": "Ribeirão|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How old was Lucas Raniel in Ribeirão Preto?",
                    "score": 0.8505,
                    "answers": "old|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where was Lucas Raniel from?",
                    "score": 0.8246,
                    "answers": "state of Sao Paulo|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the consequences of intentional transmission of HIV in Ribeirão Preto?",
                    "score": 0.7838,
                    "answers": "that|mark\t,|punct\t |dep\t,|punct\t,|punct\t,|punct\twhat|nsubj\tthe|det\tof HIV|prep\tHIV|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the death of Lucas Raniel?",
                    "score": 0.7479,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "He has lived with the virus for three years and became accused of deliberately spreading it.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did bbc.com report on 08/07/2017",
                    "answer": "He has lived with the virus for three years and became accused of deliberately spreading it"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How long has he been with the virus?",
                    "score": 0.9027,
                    "answers": "that He has lived with the virus for three years and became accused of deliberately spreading it|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Dr. George Flinn do with the virus?",
                    "score": 0.8639,
                    "answers": "became|auxpass\tbecame accused of deliberately spreading it|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the virus?",
                    "score": 0.7967,
                    "answers": "the virus|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the virus that the virus has spread?",
                    "score": 0.781,
                    "answers": "He|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the virus and the virus?",
                    "score": 0.7797,
                    "answers": "with the virus|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'Last year they created a WhatsApp group with a photo of me and they talked about AIDS going on.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the topic of the WhatsApp group?",
                    "answer": "AIDS"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the WhatsApp group say about AIDS going on?",
                    "score": 0.8251,
                    "answers": "about AIDS going on|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who created the WhatsApp group with a photo of me and HIV?",
                    "score": 0.8146,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that ' Last year they created a WhatsApp group with a photo of me and they talked about AIDS going on|ROOT\ton 08/07/2017|prep\t'|punct\tLast|amod\tthey|nsubj\tthat ' Last year they created a WhatsApp group with a photo of me and they talked about AIDS going on|ccomp\ta|det\ta|det\tthey|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between HIV and AIDS?",
                    "score": 0.745,
                    "answers": "AIDS going on|pcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the WhatsApp group?",
                    "score": 0.7316,
                    "answers": "they talked about AIDS going on|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the WhatsApp group that was created in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.6944,
                    "answers": "of me|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "That rumor spread and when I discovered it I was shocked ', he relates.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What reaction did he have when he found out about the rumor?",
                    "answer": "shocked"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the rumor spread?",
                    "score": 0.6692,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that That rumor spread and when I discovered it I was shocked '|ccomp\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tThat|det\tThat rumor|nsubj\tthat That rumor spread and when I discovered it I was shocked|ccomp\tand|cc\twhen|advmod\tI|nsubj\twhen I discovered it|advcl\tit|dobj\tI|nsubj\twhen I discovered it I was shocked|conj\tshocked|acomp\t'|punct\t,|punct\the|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that That rumor spread and when I discovered it I was shocked ' , he relates|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "At that time, Raniel was in treatment against the virus and had undetectable viral load.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was Raniel's viral load?",
                    "answer": "undetectable viral load"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was Raniel being treated for?",
                    "score": 0.8794,
                    "answers": "that At that time , Raniel was in treatment against the virus and had undetectable viral load|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Raniel have to say about the virus?",
                    "score": 0.8624,
                    "answers": "the virus|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the treatment for Raniel in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.8501,
                    "answers": "treatment against the virus|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the viral load of Raniel in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.8481,
                    "answers": "had undetectable viral load|conj\tundetectable viral load|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Raniel being in treatment against the virus?",
                    "score": 0.8448,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that At that time , Raniel was in treatment against the virus and had undetectable viral load|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'I went to the bars and felt like they were looking at me, a lot of people walked away and I isolated myself.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.bbc.com report on 08/07/2017",
                    "answer": "'I went to the bars and felt like they were looking at me, a lot of people walked away and I isolated myself"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Why did people walk away and isolate themselves?",
                    "score": 0.7348,
                    "answers": "a lot of people walked away and I isolated myself|conj\tI isolated myself|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people were looking at Gary Johnson after he left the bar?",
                    "score": 0.6366,
                    "answers": "the|det\tthey|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people walked away from the bar?",
                    "score": 0.5782,
                    "answers": "to the bars|prep\tof people|prep\tpeople|pobj\taway|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Gary Johnson and Scott Israel?",
                    "score": 0.5775,
                    "answers": "like|mark\twere|aux"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between walking away from a bar and seeing people looking at you?",
                    "score": 0.5526,
                    "answers": "that ' I went to the bars and felt like they were looking at me , a lot of people walked away and I isolated myself|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "He lived going from faculty to work and from work to home ', says Raniel.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How did Raniel live?",
                    "answer": "going from faculty to work and from work to home"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of where Raniel lived from faculty to work?",
                    "score": 0.7122,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that He lived going from faculty to work and from work to home ' , says Raniel|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Raniel and the faculty?",
                    "score": 0.6533,
                    "answers": "faculty|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between faculty and home?",
                    "score": 0.6323,
                    "answers": "that He lived going from faculty to work and from work to home|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The publicist reveals that he reached the end of hanging himself in the window of his room for a whole night.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the publicist say he did at the end of the night?",
                    "answer": "hanging himself in the window of his room"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How long did he hang himself in his room?",
                    "score": 0.7743,
                    "answers": "of hanging himself in the window of his room for a whole night|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How long did the publicist hang himself in a room?",
                    "score": 0.7714,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that The publicist reveals that he reached the end of hanging himself in the window of his room for a whole night|ROOT\tthe end of hanging himself in the window of his room for a whole night|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the man who hung himself in a room for a whole night?",
                    "score": 0.6298,
                    "answers": "The|det\tthe|det\tthe|det\tof his room|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "It's sad to talk about it, but I don't think it's right to stop mentioning it because people think about it and it can't be that way.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Why did bbc.com say it wasn't right to stop mentioning it?",
                    "answer": "people think about it and it can't be that way"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does it mean to talk about it?",
                    "score": 0.8171,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that It 's sad to talk about it , but I do n't think it 's right to stop mentioning it because people think about it and it ca n't be that way|ROOT\tthat It 's sad to talk about it , but I do n't think it 's right to stop mentioning it because people think about it and it ca n't be that way|ccomp\tsad|acomp\tto talk about it|xcomp\tmentioning it|xcomp\tit ca n't be that way|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people think about it and it can't be that way?",
                    "score": 0.7284,
                    "answers": "about it|prep\tpeople|nsubj\tbecause people think about it and it ca n't be that way|advcl\tabout it|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of people who think it's right to stop mentioning it?",
                    "score": 0.7002,
                    "answers": "I do n't think it 's right to stop mentioning it because people think about it and it ca n't be that way|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "You can't kill yourself because of a disease, you have to beat it and you don't give yourself up.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that you can't kill yourself because of a disease?",
                    "answer": "08/07/2017"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Can you kill yourself because of a disease?",
                    "score": 0.8595,
                    "answers": "n't|neg\tn't|neg"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does it mean to kill yourself?",
                    "score": 0.8136,
                    "answers": "to beat it|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the definition of a disease?",
                    "score": 0.7235,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tYou|nsubj\tca|aux\tthat You ca n't kill yourself because of a disease , you have to beat it and you do n't give yourself up|ccomp\tyourself|dobj\tbecause of a disease|prep\tof|pcomp\ta|det\ta disease|pobj\t,|punct\tyou|nsubj\tyou have to beat it and you do n't give yourself up|conj\tto|aux\tit|dobj\tand|cc\tyou|nsubj\tdo|aux\tyourself|dobj\tup|prt"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "But evil and prejudice make you close down and give in to a depression you don't even realize 'explains Luke.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What does evil and prejudice make you give in to?",
                    "answer": "a depression you don't even realize"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Luke say about fear and prejudice?",
                    "score": 0.7215,
                    "answers": "you do n't even realize|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Luke's depression?",
                    "score": 0.7186,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tevil and prejudice|nsubj\tprejudice|conj\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that But evil and prejudice make you close down and give in to a depression you do n't even realize ' explains Luke|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Luke's depression?",
                    "score": 0.7179,
                    "answers": "a|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the definition of a depression?",
                    "score": 0.7018,
                    "answers": "you close down and give in to a depression you do n't even realize|ccomp\tgive in to a depression you do n't even realize|conj\tto a depression you do n't even realize|prep\ta depression you do n't even realize|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Luke's relationship with hate and prejudice?",
                    "score": 0.6351,
                    "answers": "do|aux\tn't|neg"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Raniel discovered HIV positive in December of .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who discovered HIV positive in December of 2017?",
                    "answer": "Raniel"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When did Raniel discover HIV positive?",
                    "score": 0.9336,
                    "answers": "in December of|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "When was Raniel discovered HIV positive?",
                    "score": 0.9306,
                    "answers": "that Raniel discovered HIV positive in December of|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Dr. Raniel find in December of 2017?",
                    "score": 0.8853,
                    "answers": "HIV positive|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Raniel's HIV positive?",
                    "score": 0.8687,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that Raniel discovered HIV positive in December of|ROOT\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tof|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between HIV positive and HIV positive?",
                    "score": 0.8603,
                    "answers": "positive|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "He says he thinks he was infected three months earlier, after meeting with a guy he'd met through a mobile app.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "When did he think he was infected three months earlier?",
                    "score": 0.8302,
                    "answers": "that He says he thinks he was infected three months earlier , after meeting with a guy he 'd met through a mobile app|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the date of the first time he was infected?",
                    "score": 0.6976,
                    "answers": "he was infected three months earlier , after meeting with a guy he 'd met through a mobile app|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the man who was infected by a mobile app?",
                    "score": 0.6652,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the mobile app?",
                    "score": 0.599,
                    "answers": "mobile|compound\ta mobile app|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the man he met through a mobile app?",
                    "score": 0.5713,
                    "answers": "after meeting with a guy he 'd met through a mobile app|prep\ta guy he 'd met through a mobile app|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'I had come home drunk, after a party, and I met the boy.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that they had come home drunk?",
                    "answer": "08/07/2017"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between a drunk and a drunk at a party?",
                    "score": 0.7302,
                    "answers": "after a party|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the man who was drunk after a party?",
                    "score": 0.73,
                    "answers": "that ' I had come home drunk , after a party , and I met the boy|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between the boy and the man?",
                    "score": 0.6538,
                    "answers": "the boy|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "We had a little chat and we met that very night.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that we had a little chat?",
                    "answer": "08/07/2017"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the date of the meeting?",
                    "score": 0.7691,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that We had a little chat and we met that very night|ROOT\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tand|cc\twe met that very night|conj\tthat|det\tvery|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of the meeting?",
                    "score": 0.7522,
                    "answers": "that We had a little chat and we met that very night|ccomp\tlittle|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Scott Walker and Bill Clinton?",
                    "score": 0.7224,
                    "answers": "we|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "I went to his house, we kept drinking and I ended up losing my senses.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did bbc.com report on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "I went to his house, we kept drinking"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the relationship between Scott Walker and Gary Johnson?",
                    "score": 0.7093,
                    "answers": "that I went to his house , we kept drinking and I ended up losing my senses|ccomp\twe kept drinking and I ended up losing my senses|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the man who was drinking at his house in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.6351,
                    "answers": "his|poss"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the relationship between Bogdanoff and Scott Walker?",
                    "score": 0.6153,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the cause of the loss of senses?",
                    "score": 0.6084,
                    "answers": "I ended up losing my senses|conj\tlosing my senses|xcomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In the middle of the morning he took me to the room, but I have a very vague memory ', he relates.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the bbc report about my memory?",
                    "answer": "I have a very vague memory"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the earliest memory of the person who took him to the room?",
                    "score": 0.6231,
                    "answers": "a very vague memory|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the room where the incident took place?",
                    "score": 0.5751,
                    "answers": "the room|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Raniel points out that the next day he remembered that he had a sexual relationship.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who said that he remembered that he had a sexual relationship the next day?",
                    "answer": "Raniel"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did Raniel know that he had a sexual relationship with a man?",
                    "score": 0.877,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tthat|mark\tthat|mark"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Raniel think about his sexual relationship?",
                    "score": 0.8183,
                    "answers": "that he had a sexual relationship|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Raniel and his partner?",
                    "score": 0.7102,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 08/07/2017|prep\the|nsubj\the|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'I remember little of that night, but I knew he had done it without a condom.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.bbc.com report on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "'I remember little of that night, but I knew he had done it without a condom"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many condoms were there in that night?",
                    "score": 0.8683,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep\t,|punct\thad|aux\ta|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the condoms used in the incident?",
                    "score": 0.7146,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the date of the incident?",
                    "score": 0.6874,
                    "answers": "little of that night|dobj\tof that night|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Before discovering the virus, Lucas points out that he came looking for the man again.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on the virus on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "www.bbc.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Who discovered the virus?",
                    "score": 0.8832,
                    "answers": "discovering the virus|pcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who did Lucas come looking for after he discovered the virus?",
                    "score": 0.8247,
                    "answers": "came|aux"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was the first person to discover the virus?",
                    "score": 0.808,
                    "answers": "Before discovering the virus|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who was the man who came looking for the virus?",
                    "score": 0.7553,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that Before discovering the virus , Lucas points out that he came looking for the man again|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the source of evidence of the virus before it was discovered?",
                    "score": 0.7437,
                    "answers": "the virus|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'I started to get sick and I got to look for it on WhatsApp.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.bbc.com report on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "'I started to get sick and I got to look for it on WhatsApp"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the number of sick people on WhatsApp?",
                    "score": 0.6629,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\t'|punct\tI|nsubj\tto|aux\tto get sick|xcomp\tsick|acomp\tI|nsubj\tto|aux\tit|pobj\tWhatsApp|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the person who got sick on WhatsApp in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.6612,
                    "answers": "that ' I started to get sick and I got to look for it on WhatsApp|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the link between WhatsApp and facebook?",
                    "score": 0.6375,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that ' I started to get sick and I got to look for it on WhatsApp|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Facebook and WhatsApp?",
                    "score": 0.6082,
                    "answers": "and|cc"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "I told him about what was going on and I told him I hadn't had condom-free sex with anyone else.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did bbc.com say about condom-free sex?",
                    "answer": "I told him about what was going on"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is condom-free sex?",
                    "score": 0.7804,
                    "answers": "condom - free sex|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between condoms and sex?",
                    "score": 0.7486,
                    "answers": "I told him I had n't had condom - free sex with anyone else|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the condom-free sex with anyone else?",
                    "score": 0.7447,
                    "answers": "condom|npadvmod\tcondom - free|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the condom-free sex between the man and the man?",
                    "score": 0.6895,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Raniel is another young man who believes he has been the victim of intentional transmission of HIV, but chose not to report the case.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is another young man who believes he has been the victim of intentional transmission of HIV?",
                    "answer": "Raniel"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did Raniel commit intentional transmission of HIV?",
                    "score": 0.9059,
                    "answers": "who believes he has been the victim of intentional transmission of HIV , but chose not to report the case|relcl\tnot|neg"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Raniel do to make it public?",
                    "score": 0.8332,
                    "answers": "chose not to report the case|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Raniel and HIV?",
                    "score": 0.7383,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep\tHIV|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'There's no way to prove it was intentional, plus, I think a mistake of mine caused it because I was drinking a lot.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.bbc.com report on 08/07/2017?",
                    "answer": "'There's no way to prove it was intentional, plus, I think a mistake of mine caused it"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the evidence of intentional drinking?",
                    "score": 0.7703,
                    "answers": "no way to prove it was intentional|attr\tto prove it was intentional|relcl\tintentional|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between drinking a lot of alcohol and drinking drinking?",
                    "score": 0.7535,
                    "answers": "I think a mistake of mine caused it because I was drinking a lot|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of drinking a lot?",
                    "score": 0.7122,
                    "answers": "it was intentional|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "I don't have pain, I hope it's okay and don't do it again.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that I don't have pain?",
                    "answer": "08/07/2017"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the symptoms of pain?",
                    "score": 0.8688,
                    "answers": "I do n't have pain|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Dr. George Flinn's pain?",
                    "score": 0.7683,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that I do n't have pain , I hope it 's okay and do n't do it again|ROOT\tthat I do n't have pain , I hope it 's okay and do n't do it again|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between pain and pain?",
                    "score": 0.7432,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tI|nsubj\tdo|aux\tn't|neg\tpain|dobj\t,|punct\tI|nsubj\tit|nsubj\tokay|acomp\tand|cc\tdo|aux\tn't|neg\tdo n't do it again|conj\tit|dobj\tagain|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the website that claims that I don't have pain and hope it's okay?",
                    "score": 0.7019,
                    "answers": "it 's okay|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "TrendsThe three young people mentioned in this report comprise a range of population that has shown an increase in infection rates.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many young people were mentioned in the Trends report?",
                    "answer": "three"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the rates of HIV and TB?",
                    "score": 0.8569,
                    "answers": "in infection rates|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the rate of infection rates?",
                    "score": 0.8489,
                    "answers": "an increase in infection rates|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the current rate of infection rates for young people?",
                    "score": 0.8327,
                    "answers": "infection|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many young people were mentioned in the report?",
                    "score": 0.8243,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tTrendsThe|det\tTrendsThe three young people mentioned in this report|nsubj\tmentioned in this report|acl\tthis|det\ta|det\tthat|nsubj\tan|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between HIV and TB?",
                    "score": 0.8009,
                    "answers": "that has shown an increase in infection rates|relcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Ministry of Health data show that the rate of men from  to  years with AIDS almost tripled from  to  (from  cases per  thousand inhabitants to ).",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the rate of HIV among men with AIDS?",
                    "score": 0.8033,
                    "answers": "  years with AIDS|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the rate of HIV-positive men in South Africa in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.7519,
                    "answers": "that Ministry of Health data show that the rate of men from   to   years with AIDS almost tripled from|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "There was also a large increase in the range from  to  years (from  cases to  thousand inhabitants to ).",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people live in South Africa?",
                    "score": 0.8085,
                    "answers": "thousand inhabitants to|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the population of South Africa in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.7709,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat There was also a large increase in the range from|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many cases were there per year in Africa in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.7585,
                    "answers": "  cases|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people were in the country in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.7298,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that There was also a large increase in the range from   to   years ( from   cases to   thousand inhabitants to )|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the population of the country?",
                    "score": 0.6741,
                    "answers": "  to|dep\tyears (|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Experts suggest that reasons are linked to factors such as the emergence of applications that facilitate casual sexual encounters and the decline of sex education programs in schools.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is one reason for the decline of sex education programs in schools?",
                    "answer": "the emergence of applications that facilitate casual sexual encounters"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the decline of sex education programs in schools?",
                    "score": 0.7516,
                    "answers": "factors such as the emergence of applications that facilitate casual sexual encounters and the decline of sex education programs in schools|pobj\tsuch as the emergence of applications that facilitate casual sexual encounters and the decline of sex education programs in schools|prep\tthe emergence of applications that facilitate casual sexual encounters and the decline of sex education programs in schools|pobj\tcasual sexual encounters|dobj\tthe decline of sex education programs in schools|conj\tof sex education programs in schools|prep\tsex education|compound\tsex education programs in schools|pobj\tin schools|prep\tschools|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The orientation of the Ministry of Health is to use condoms in sexual relations always.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of using condoms in sexual relations?",
                    "score": 0.8898,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that The orientation of the Ministry of Health is to use condoms in sexual relations always|ROOT\tthat The orientation of the Ministry of Health is to use condoms in sexual relations always|ccomp\tto use condoms in sexual relations always|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the orientation of the Ministry of Health for sexual relations?",
                    "score": 0.8505,
                    "answers": "in sexual relations|prep\tsexual relations|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In case of suspected exposure to HIV, the Single Health System offers Post-Exhibition Prophylaxis (PEP), which is an antiretroviral treatment for  days, aimed at preventing infection of the virus.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What does PEP stand for?",
                    "answer": "Post-Exhibition Prophylaxis"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How long does it take to prevent infection of HIV?",
                    "score": 0.8392,
                    "answers": "days|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does PEP stand for?",
                    "score": 0.7118,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that In case of suspected exposure to HIV , the Single Health System offers Post - Exhibition Prophylaxis ( PEP ) , which is an antiretroviral treatment for   days , aimed at preventing infection of the virus|ROOT\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tIn case of suspected exposure to HIV|prep\tcase of suspected exposure to HIV|pobj\tof suspected exposure to HIV|prep\tsuspected|amod\tsuspected exposure to HIV|pobj\tto HIV|prep\tHIV|pobj\t,|punct\tthe|det\tSingle|compound\tHealth|compound\tthat In case of suspected exposure to HIV , the Single Health System offers Post - Exhibition Prophylaxis ( PEP ) , which is an antiretroviral treatment for|ccomp\tPost|compound\t-|compound\tExhibition|compound\tPost - Exhibition Prophylaxis ( PEP ) , which is an antiretroviral treatment for|dobj\t(|punct\tPEP|appos\t)|punct\t,|punct\twhich|nsubj\twhich is an antiretroviral treatment for|relcl\tan|det\tantiretroviral|amod\tan antiretroviral treatment for|attr\tfor|prep\t,|punct\tat preventing infection of the virus|prep\tinfection of the virus|dobj\tof the virus|prep\tthe|det\tthe virus|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of Post-Exhibition Prophylaxis?",
                    "score": 0.6754,
                    "answers": "preventing infection of the virus|pcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is PEP?",
                    "score": 0.6722,
                    "answers": "  days|dep\taimed at preventing infection of the virus|advcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The procedure should be started within a maximum of  hours after contact with HIV.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How long should it take to start the HIV procedure?",
                    "score": 0.8785,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat The procedure should be started within a maximum of|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the best way to prevent contact with HIV?",
                    "score": 0.8381,
                    "answers": "contact with HIV|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the maximum hours after contact with HIV?",
                    "score": 0.8128,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that The procedure should be started within a maximum of   hours after contact with HIV|ROOT\tthat|mark\ta maximum of|pobj\t |dep\t  hours|dobj\tHIV|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "It is estimated that in Brazil there are  a thousand people living with the virus and that they do not yet know it.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people are estimated to be living with the virus in Brazil?",
                    "answer": "a thousand"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people are living with the virus in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.8881,
                    "answers": "living with the virus|acl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people live in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.8723,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that It is estimated that in Brazil there are   a thousand people living with the virus and that they do not yet know it|ROOT\ton 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tIt|nsubjpass\tis|auxpass\tthat It is estimated that in Brazil there are|ccomp\tthat|mark\tin Brazil|prep\tthere|expl\tthat in Brazil there are|advcl\ta|quantmod\ta thousand|nummod\twith the virus|prep\tthe|det\tthe virus|pobj\tand|cc\tthat|mark\tthey|nsubj\tdo|aux\tnot|neg\tyet|advmod\tthat they do not yet know it|conj\tit|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Other  would already be aware, but do not use medicines.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 08/07/2017 that Other would already be aware, but not use medicines?",
                    "answer": "www.bbc.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Other medicine use?",
                    "score": 0.904,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that Other   would already be aware , but do not use medicines|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Of the  people living with HIV in Brazil, around  were already diagnosed and  started treatment.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report on the number of people living with HIV in Brazil?",
                    "answer": "08/07/2017"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people have HIV in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.9213,
                    "answers": "on 08/07/2017|prep\tthat|mark\tthe|det\twith HIV|prep\tHIV|pobj\tin Brazil|prep\t,|punct\taround|mark\talready|advmod\tand|cc\t |dep\tstarted treatment|dep\ttreatment|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people live with HIV in Brazil?",
                    "score": 0.9163,
                    "answers": "Of the   people living with HIV in Brazil|dative\tthe   people living with HIV in Brazil|dep\tpeople living with HIV in Brazil|pobj\tliving with HIV in Brazil|acl\tOf the   people living with HIV in Brazil , around  |dep\tthat Of the   people living with HIV in Brazil , around   were already diagnosed and   started treatment|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people living with HIV in Brazil have been diagnosed and treated?",
                    "score": 0.9132,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 08/07/2017 that Of the   people living with HIV in Brazil , around   were already diagnosed and   started treatment|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people in Brazil were diagnosed with HIV in 2017?",
                    "score": 0.9015,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}